Hello, this is...were here at build twenty fifteen would you guys
...introduce yourselves and telling us what
...efforts on...general manager for office extensibility all nice and
...like about technical product manager
and office marketing can you tell us a little bit about why you're fear and one
...guys made the absolutely this is a big week for us we really launched up the
notion of office as a platform we got a great opportunity to get up on stage
with such a earlier this weekand,
demo sort of the full range of what people can do with office and,
it was a big opportunity for us to...three key messages about
using office to connect to a really broad user population got
...fact in some ways using office to help advertise your servicing connect users
back to the capabilities you offer the second around all of the dating capabilities that
...and office three sixty five and how you can use those to build
richer apps that are really all about getting people...helping people get work done by a
and key part of that is these this is the data in content that users really
love and care about it is the documents that they have worked on it is important meetings that they go
...the valuable conversations that they have and you can take advantage of that in your application so
what does this extensibility look like what kind of things can you do and
is x sensibility sort-of only restricted to the...excel can-you build extension just for excel
and abalone for word how does...it's all...like, yeah, I think the average sort of thing about being a build is that, you know,
traditionally when we were building for like sharepoint...for office we were talking
just office developers or just a sharepoint developers and now with the model any web
...directly into powerpoint excel word and, you know,
or even sharepoint but it doesn't have to be in l products, you know,
we can extend our user experience of the
one-point-two billion use of office but we can also do is say well if you already have an existing
web application your sas...startup in the valley you can connect into
our api and leverage like a content so the nature is the
evil we can provide a mechanism to get those things three or we can actually
allow people to discover these things...office store and, users can grammars things directly in-store
...show us what we could do short so if I just jump in here
too my experience serious I will go into excel hit
...the right-hand side is we have this notion of a tossed...and on the right-hand side
is an example of an sap them we put together which will actually show
...the keynote one of the compelling things with these...is that they don't just work in
the desktop versions of office I if I have the or if I'm in the online version
...browser...these adding to work natively in those
...that with the same sort of like...I imagine...correctly if I'm wrong you're building
a new project for office and you're saying that same project work across all of
the versions absolutely and, that's a...as we light up those experience is not just in the next
one's going to target is a new android apps were powerpoint excelled...
preview right now and they will come once we ship the windows ten versions of offices well these...
in the work their without any code changes...tools so it's a really compelling way of kind of the
...reach out to an audience that may be use a web developer...reach before and,
for me I think personally like I spend way too much time in outlook with
...to get into that audience of we said
four hundred-million uses actually using that out dot com experience...for that is a really compelling
...doing...that is a pretty good thing out what these projects look like for developer
so that naturally we give the best...visual studio right so right now you can do the
fall new projects and jump straight into and build an ad in there but,
for instance we have angular developers essentially just...within their own idea they used to
...sublime or whatever like notepad they can do whatever they like in there and essentially
...and manifests xml against added into the store all they side load it
and that points to the web at where the...runs...these are actually web applications that are running
inside of,...the easiest way to think about it is that
you've built a service that lives on the web and you want to really light that up across the office and
points so what office is going to go do is connect your service get the html and javascript and
...it within the context of office I give you an object model where you can go and manipulate
the document content so that you can have rich capabilities integrated inside of the of
...so that truly makes it so that it works
everywhere it's right all right so sorry...kind of derail
you as a really good right so this example here this some sap of prototype
right now using just stand html javascript I'm on the right-hand side,
... the our of this scenario is a lot of people...using
xcel to edit manipulate data what I can do is I can come in and like pick data model that's
being pulled from sap isolates and connect to that is she going to
...that data directly into excel is
...that by using this javascript library cool office js to inject tool that data directly into the
...the nice thing about the scenarios say I'm kind of...my data from sap directly
and excel so maybe I...about my age I'm not really...and maybe I'm thirty four?
...go through an update that data than us but is before site evil that data back to
...completely compare...we'll do is actually use the office js
libraries that...there was a change the data from when it was first inserted
and then I can actually go through and say yes I'm happy with that change and the differences between my data
...update that push that data...website...less really cool so there's two aspects
of what's going on there's the actual x for ui that you get to put in and then
there's the interaction with the actual document whatever it may be right so
...benefiting from...in this...sap but you can imagine that to be any type of enterprise
development scenario where I'm reaching from data from elsewhere and using the our of excel
...the nice thing here is again this would work on the it works on the browser as well so no matter where
...is this animal actually work across platforms couple
other comments about this one this is actually built on top of sat gateway from microsoft so they worked
with us to build some enabling technology that wires sap data up for off and
...data and that makes it easy for us to integrated...office and this but you could also build like, for example,
your own web api...resuming push...back and forth into documents where
threat like let's be honest the best tool for doing any kind of
work nowadays excel because everyone is using...using excelled...as
well-put your stuff in there...back-up hikes...got into this would just never example this is something was
...is the guys and imaging cops a bunch of students from china actually wrote this actually
wouldn the imaging...this for the category
there in what they've done is if I just change...blanks...
Where I'm presenting...disappear which makes it always a little bit tricky so I...to the
...the ribbon here and you go to inset my apps actually
...approach so we had the shape of a toss
...in excel in this instance where actually...to injects content directly into a powerpoint
slide which is essentially an...frame of...html?
The...here was the students their teaches with teach-in to code and they kept kind of
...directly into the slide and never formatted it was very hard to talk to that
card so what I can do here is I have a samples...here which is an javascript
...auto-detects that language allows me to kinda go in here and see that
card some of the nice things I've done is I can easily
...zooming that cody using that using that plugging the.
And,...can also do is I can collapsed down the different functions...go in here and.
I...collapse down the functions...from starting to talk about this code I can start...this
...bits that I can expand it and I can actually go through and say
...by click the print welcome on here will start to highlight the references of whether print welcome is in
the rest of the script...this is something these guys put together in a few weeks
...very little experience...office but, you know,
they had html javascript experience to understand how they could interact with that model
...so I powerpoint...also...scenario in the...they actually use this in their classrooms and,
actually now this app is up in the store so people can go and
...music and get that experience yet so, if I go ahead here in the ribbon you can see I can click on the
store that will launch...of our store apps are available in that ecosystem
...everyone was actually...that was built and we first releases in the store and again,
that's level...directly into a powerpoint slide and have kind of that so this
...an interesting thing because now it's not just you're making something
for you but now you could distributed inside of app store...office...to talk a little
bit more about that well as you can see up here directly from within powerpoint or any of
the office applications you can connect to the store you can find applications we're now calling
...that map to your particular scenario you can also go to the website to find others
one of the key things about this is were excited about developers putting at ends up here in sharing
them broadly round-the-world with also enabled corporate store where
an organization can distribute their apps and add-in size so is very much about a corporate
it developer building a solution that makes their employees more productive
...broadly distributing it throughout the organization and the nice thing is it starts to
remembered fully because I'm signed into office if I've added...at one of in
...desktop version of ick so what I jump on excel my...in the recently use that inness as well
...I can just add that directly so it's really neat in terms of it follows you around the
...experience in one last thing about app distribution it turns out that they
actually get saved into the document so jeremy saved this presentation and then mailed it
...when you open it up it would have a picture of what the
add-in was doing and then would invite you to go get it so that you would have the same...experience and it
...actually violently distributes the
...that way or not opening something...breaks and that's what I know...and...if
you're developer you get to think about how those great solutions get distributed by users on your behalf
the awesome and the other aspect of it is the add-in...cone
...getting...reaching all the office uses but in terms of if you're user inside office
...five you're living within the web browser to check outlook online or
...using out delve product to understand what's going on within your organization would actually allowed you
now that you can be part of this experience to so in this demo hey you can say there's a bunch of towels
here app launcher to apps the we provide for free as part of the office
...experience such as delvin the video portal
and one node one drive but we also have this example here which is the program property
manager...which we actually had a presentation this week on which is a hero demo we put together
the kinda highlight how you can go and connects...all of our api is but live within your
...experience so in this scenario here the property manager here has been built using
...on nbc's hosted measure is single...experience so uses the office
...five credentials...to lock me in is my the property manager and the scenario here
is if I jump through...this properties I managing again as a web developer
on building this experience all this data innocence is actually store in sharepoint so
we can leverage along the benefits of sharepoint as a platform overeats workflow
...version history the properties changing
or uploading falls images there too and some of the new things that we that
...this week is that we've introduced new api is so for instance
...the property manager is the inspectors go out and look at these rentals and they
filming videos may be damage things...houses we know things go wrong as
...there's a little...here that's uploaded into the video pool office
free six five...that's actually showing is the streaming...
asher media services directly through into the browser here and they've leverage the api
sweatshop...this video directly from the property manage...we've built
in shipped in is open sourcing get hop that's awesome so this is really cool stuff and
I like it because I mean it leverages other people are know how to use and
...hook into stuff that everybody uses...less than distributor app on your behalf
sort of viral solve ax attribute a comment about was
...web sdk intel's little bit about that, yeah, it's actually in this notion of getting rich
...for office three sixty five so you can build solutions
that access more data and have more capabilities where enabling people to build websites
that have rich real-time communication built right into it using the preview of the
...web sdk that we announced this week so in essence you...like you're betting
...web that's exaggerate...but you can do it in the context of your web
solution so you can of all the data that users want to care about you can imagine
...see scenarios where you could have help-desk people talking
...customers...really and they don't have to leave your experience in order to do
it so there's a restful set of api is that enable presence notification and,
chat and then you can embed the directly the...control for real-time video
...making that from...cults, yeah, and, I think the benefit there is the
...both...and those imbed scenarios is the,
... it saves you flicking context so I don't have to go and alt tab...
have like three screens sky...my environment is just living within that one experience my
uses don't have to keep jumping between different things all right so where can
developers growed to learn more maybe even get started yep so if they go to if I
could type office depth office dot com that landing pages where you can get
all of our resources we have over eighty hours a video-on-demand trying
for free their and hands-on labs you can go and kind of very easily get speed building
...for outlook a word pap...excel we have all links off
...documentationI do a weekly podcast...I...and stuff so it's
...place to go...get started with any of this development office for any parting words to developers that
are watching what we really hope that they see the opportunity and we hope that it's clear what we want
to accomplish here which is we really believe in making the end-users a lot more productive in the
flow how they do their work we're going to do everything possible to make sure that developers can be super
productive
right delivering those solutions very good and for-you I think the opportunity thing for me is what
relieves we've seen a lot of isv that are here actually today with the on the expo hole where they've
...the authentication of...three six five and they may be integrated without calendar
...and I've seen a massive boost up to twenty five percent of this sign up
snell coming because the office...for convertible are already there
...office so it just adds a whole level of discover ability from
...store of the user base...been...reach before so there's a huge
opportunity for that all thanks so much for giving us this really good information I know I'm excited
...even start get started thanks so much for watching we again
...and we'll see you next time take care?